The Reese Family Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- The Mesier Family, 1700 - 1891; 2; Boxes: 15 - 23 Folders: 1 - 21, 1 -34, 1 - 41, 1 - 43, 1 - 12, 1 - 44, 1 - 28, 1 - 12, 1 - 2
  - Indentures, 1700 - 1891; 2.1; Boxes: 15 - 19 Folders: 1 - 21, 1 -34, 1 - 41, 1 - 43, 1 - 12
    - Silvanus Pine and wife Juda of Rumbout precinct in Dutchess County in the Colony of New York and Zacharias Van Voorhis of the same place, 1772 October 13 (Folder 16, Box 15)
    - John Smyth, Henry Cuyler and Peter Mesier of the City of New York, 1773 April 19 (Folder 17, Box 15)
    - Petrus Bogardus and Hendrick Schenck, 1774 January 13 (Folder 18, Box 15)
    - Joseph Hopkins of Kent in the County of Litchfield in the Colony of Connecticut and Elizabeth [Height?], 1774 February 7 (Folder 19, Box 15)
    - Peter Silvester of the City of Albany and Peter Mesier of the City of New York [2 items], 1774 April 25-26 (Folder 20, Box 15)
    - Nicholas Brewer and wife Sarah of Rumbout precinct in Dutchess County in the Colony of New York and Matthew Van Bunschoten, 1777 April 3-4 (Folder 21, Box 15)
    - Edward Churchill of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Peter Mesier of the State of New York, 1779 April 13 (Folder 1, Box 16)
    - Edward Churchill and Peter Mesier [2 items], 1779 June 15 - August 6 (Folder 2, Box 16)
    - Matthew Mesier and James Wood, 1783 March 29 (Folder 3, Box 16)
    - John Pennoyer of the City of Hudson in the State of New York and Peter Mesier of the City of New York, 1785 November 26 (Folder 4, Box 16)
    - Edward Churchill of Rumbout precinct in Dutchess County in the State of New York and Peter Mesier of the same place, 1787 March 28 - August 13 (Folder 5, Box 16)
    - William Brewer of Rumbout precinct in Dutchess County in the State of New York and Peter Mesier of the same place [2 items], 1787 April 22 (Folder 6, Box 16)
    - Jacob Van Voorhis of Fishkill in Dutchess County and John Lawrence of the City of New York [2 items], 1788 September 1-2 (Folder 7, Box 16)
    - Zachariah Crump of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Peter Mesier of the same place, 1789 April 15 (Folder 8, Box 16)
    - John Dewitt of Dutchess County and Peter Mesier, 1790 July 27 (Folder 9, Box 16)
    - Simon I. Frear of Poughkeepsie precinct in Dutchess County in the State of New York and Rutgers Van Brunt of Queens and Kings County [2 items], 1788 December 5-6 (Folder 10, Box 16)
    - Nicholas Brower and wife Mary of the City of New York and Peter Mesier of Fishkill in Dutchess County [2 items], 1790 April 14-15 (Folder 11, Box 16)
    - Hickey Bates and wife Eve of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Rutgers Van Brunt of Kings County [2 items], 1791 March 1 (Folder 12, Box 16)
    - John Lawrence of the City of New York and Peter Mesier of the same place, 1792 June 5 (Folder 13, Box 16)
    - Samuel, Phillip and William B. Ver Planck and Peter Mesier of Dutchess County, 1792 August 29 (Folder 14, Box 16)
    - Pierre Van Cortland of the County of Westchester County in the State of New York and Peter Mesier of Dutchess County, 1792 September 4 (Folder 15, Box 16)
    - Nicholas Wynkoop of Northampton in the County of Bucks in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania and his father, Henry Wynkoop of the same place, 1793 April 6 (Folder 16, Box 16)
    - Amos [Calkings?] of Sharon in Litchfield County in the State of Connecticut and John [Maunsell?], 1794 January 28 (Folder 17, Box 16)
    - Amos [Calkin?] of Sharon in Litchfield County in the State of Connecticut and John [Maunsell?], 1794 January 28 (Folder 18, Box 16)
    - Judah Colt of Canadaque in the County of Ontario in the State of New York and Elbert Roosevelt of the City of New York, 1795 January 5 (Folder 19, Box 16)
    - Judah Colt of Canadaque in the County of Ontario in the State of New York and Elbert Roosevelt of the City of New York, 1795 April 16 (Folder 20, Box 16)
    - Matthew Van Bunschoten, Hickey Bates and Peter Mesier, 1795 March 26 (Folder 21, Box 16)
    - Cornelius Van [Sicklen?] and wife Catharine of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Peter Mesier of the same place, 1795 May 1 (Folder 22, Box 16)
    - Hickey Bates of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Peter Mesier of the same place, 1795 May 1 (Folder 23, Box 16)
    - Cornelius Van [Sicklen?] of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Peter Mesier of the same place, 1795 May 1 (Folder 24, Box 16)
    - Hickey Bates of Fishkill in Dutchess County, T. Bailey of Poughkeepsie precinct in Dutchess County in the State of New York and Peter Mesier of Fishkill, 1795 May 3 (Folder 25, Box 16)
    - Underhill Rudd and wife Hannah and Elisha Covert of Rumbout precinct in Dutchess County in the State of New York, 1775 May 27 (Folder 26, Box 16)
    - John Pinkney of the Town of Poughkeepsie in Dutchess County in the State of New York and Hickey Bates of Fishkill in Dutchess County, 1795 June 7 (Folder 27, Box 16)
    - Nicholas Brower of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Peter and Jacobus [Monsoort?] of the same place and Abraham Fort of the Town of Poughkeepsie in Dutchess County in the State of New York, 1795 September 16 (Folder 28, Box 16)
    - Nicholas Brower of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Peter and Jacobus [Monsoort?] of the same place and Abraham Fort of the Town of Poughkeepsie in Dutchess County in the State of New York, 1795 September 15 (Folder 29, Box 16)
    - Edward Schoonmaker of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Samuel Cooper of the same place, 1795 September 18 (Folder 30, Box 16)
    - Bernardus Swartwout, Jr. of the City of New York, Nathaniel Montross of Westchester County in the State of New York and Peter Mesier of Dutchess County, 1796 November 13 (Folder 31, Box 16)
    - Elbert Roosevelt and his wife Jane of the City of New York and Samuel Jones, Jr. of the same place and Peter Mesier, Jr. of Dutchess County, 1797 March 23 (Folder 32, Box 16)
    - Elbert Roosevelt and his wife Jane of the City of New York and Samuel Jones, Jr. of the same place and Peter Mesier, Jr. of Dutchess County, 1797 March 23 (Folder 33, Box 16)
    - Samuel Cooper and Edward Schoonmaker and Peter Mesier, 1797 June 3 (Folder 34, Box 16)
    - John D’Witt of Dutchess County and Edward Schoonmaker, 1797 November 5 (Folder 1, Box 17)
    - Nicholas Brower, Sr. of Fishkill in Dutchess County and [Carman?] Pettit of the same place, 1798 May 1 (Folder 2, Box 17)
    - Nicholas Brower, Sr. of Fishkill in Dutchess County and James Van Beuren of Flatbush, Kings County, 1798 May 31 (Folder 3, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier and wife Catharine of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Peter Mesier, Jr. and Matthew Mesier, 1798 December 20 (Folder 4, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Cornelius Van Sicklen of Clinton Town in Dutchess County, 1795 May 2 (Folder 5, Box 17)
    - Church Wardens and Vestry of Poughkeepsie and Fishkill and Reverend Philander Chase, 1799 November 27 (Folder 6, Box 17)
    - Samuel Cooper and Peter Mesier, undated (Folder 7, Box 17)
    - Peter Hill of Newark, New Jersey and Sherman G. Rutgers of the City of New York, 1800 May 1 (Folder 8, Box 17)
    - Simon I. Frear of Poughkeepsie precinct in Dutchess County and Rutgers Van Brunt of Kings County, Long Island, 1788 December 6 (Folder 9, Box 17)
    - Rutgers Van Brunt and Peter Mesier of Dutchess County [2 items], 1798 May 1, 1802 November 18 (Folder 10, Box 17)
    - Peter and Abraham Mesier and Nicholas Brower, 1807 December 23 (Folder 11, Box 17)
    - Nicholas Brower and wife Mary of Dutchess County and Henry Terboss of Ulster County, 1804 January 2 (Folder 12, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier of the City of New York and Peter Hill, 1804 May 1 (Folder 13, Box 17)
    - Henry Terboss and wife Martha and Nicholas Brower (chain of title), 1806 June 30 (Folder 14, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier (description of a grist mill situated in the Town of Fishkill in Dutchess County and occupied by Peter Mesier, 1804 December 21 (Folder 15, Box 17)
    - Matthew Mesier and Gilbert Morgan, 1805 March 5 (Folder 16, Box 17)
    - Helena Wanshaer, widow of John Wanshaer of Rochester in Ulster County and Martinus Schoonmaker of Flatbush, Kings County, 1805 June 18 (Folder 17, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier of the City of New York and Oliver Evans of the City of Philadelphia in the State of Pennsylvania, 1805 May 28 (Folder 18, Box 17)
    - Nicholas Brower and wife Mary of Fishkill in Dutchess County and James Van Beuren of Flatbush, Kings County, 1798 May 31 (Folder 19, Box 17)
    - Jonathan Wynkoop, Reading Beatty and wife Christina, James Raguet and wife Anna, Margaretta Lombaert, Christian Wirtz and wife Maria and Henry Wynkoop, 1805 July 22 (Folder 20, Box 17)
    - Henry Wynkoop and Jonathan Wynkoop, 1806 February 9 (Folder 21, Box 17)
    - Nicholas Brower and wife Ruth of the City of New York and Henry Terboss of Dutchess County, 1806 June 30 (Folder 22, Box 17)
    - Helena Wanshaer, widow of John Wanshaer of Rochester in Ulster County and Martinus Schoonmaker of Flatbush, Kings County, 1806 May 3 (Folder 23, Box 17)
    - Henry Terboss and wife Martha of Dutchess County and Nicholas Brower of the City of New York, 1806 June 30 (Folder 24, Box 17)
    - Gabriel Annin and wife Mary of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Matthew Mesier of the same place, 1806 June 6 (Folder 25, Box 17)
    - George Tappen and Thomas Ten Eyck, 1806 July 10 (Folder 26, Box 17)
    - Gabriel Annin and wife Mary of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Gilbert Wright of the same place [2 items], 1807 September 2 (Folder 27, Box 17)
    - Nicholas Brower and wife Ruth of the City of New York and Peter and Abraham Mesier of the same place, 1807 December 18 (Folder 28, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier, Executor of Thomas Ten Eyck’s estate (receipts), 1809 May 16 (Folder 29, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier, Executor of Thomas Ten Eyck’s estate (receipts), 1809 August 2 (Folder 30, Box 17)
    - Nicholas Brower and Henry Terboss, 1806 June 30 - December (Folder 31, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier and the estate of Thomas Ten Eyck, 1810 January 10 (Folder 32, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier and Nicholas Brower, 1810 May 1 (Folder 33, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier (valuation of property), 1811 May (Folder 34, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier and wife Margaret of the City of New York and Matthew Mesier of Dutchess County, 1811 March 2 (Folder 35, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier and wife Margaret of the City of New York and Abraham Mesier and wife Joanna of Dutchess County, 1811 March 2 (Folder 36, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier and wife Margaret and Matthew Mesier and Abraham Mesier, 1811 March 2 (Folder 37, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier of the City of New York, Matthew Mesier of Dutchess County and Abraham Mesier of Dutchess County, 1811 March 2 (Folder 38, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier of the City of New York, Matthew Mesier of Dutchess County and Abraham Mesier of Dutchess County [2 items], 1811 March 2 (Folder 39, Box 17)
    - Matthew B. Tallmadge and Matthew Mesier of Fishkill in Dutchess County, 1813 April 16 (Folder 40, Box 17)
    - Dominicus Monsoort of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Abraham Mesier, 1811 April 12 (Folder 41, Box 17)
    - Peter Mesier, John Suydam, David Lydig, Abram Mesier, Peter A. Mesier and Elisa Mesier (parties of the first part) and Matthew Mesier (party of the second part), 1817 May 1 (Folder 1, Box 18)
    - Nicholas Brower of the City of New York and Henry Terboss of Dutchess County, 1806 June 30 (Folder 2, Box 18)
    - Abraham Mesier of the City of New York and Walter Channing of Newport, Rhode Island, 1811 May (Folder 3, Box 18)
    - Abraham and Matthew Mesier and Henry Terboss, 1811 May 19 (Folder 4, Box 18)
    - Abraham Mesier of Fishkill in Dutchess County and the loan officers of the County of Dutchess, 1811 September 17 (Folder 5, Box 18)
    - Gilbert I. Livingston and the loan officers of the County of Dutchess, 1785 August 9 (Folder 6, Box 18)
    - Abraham Mesier and wife Mary of the City of New York, Matthew Mesier and wife Johanna of Dutchess County and Walter Channing of Newport, Rhode Island, 1811 May 24 (Folder 7, Box 18)
    - Abraham Mesier and James Phillips, 1813 October 23 (Folder 8, Box 18)
    - Regarding the subject of the widow Schoonmaker’s claim, 1812 January 16 (Folder 9, Box 18)
    - John Ebbetts and wife Sarah, Samuel Gale and wife Elizabeth and Catharine Ebbetts and Ezra [Ludlow?], 1814 May 20 (Folder 10, Box 18)
    - Daniel and John Ebbetts (receipts), 1815 April 8 (Folder 11, Box 18)
    - Matthew Mesier and wife Joanna of Dutchess County and Abraham Mesier of the City of New York and Peter Mesier of the City of New York, 1816 November 5 (Folder 12, Box 18)
    - Promissory note (Abraham Mesier to Gordon Mumford), 1817 April 9 (Folder 13, Box 18)
    - Bills and notes to be paid, 1817 January 16 (Folder 14, Box 18)
    - Promissory note (Abraham Mesier to John Suydam), 1817 December 19 (Folder 15, Box 18)
    - Promissory notes (Abraham Mesier to Peter Schenck, Abraham Bogardus, John Cargill and others, 1818 June - October (Folder 16, Box 18)
    - Abraham Mesier and Ira Millard, 1818 April 7 (Folder 17, Box 18)
    - Abraham Mesier of the City of New York and John Suydam and David Lydig of the City of New York [4 items], 1818 July 1 (Folder 18, Box 18)
    - Abraham Mesier of Dutchess County and [Obijah?] Patterson of the same place, 1819 March 8 (Folder 19, Box 18)
    - Abraham Mesier and John Delavergne, 1820 February 21 (Folder 20, Box 18)
    - Inventory of common stock (Matthew Mesier), 1821 April 9 (Folder 21, Box 18)
    - Matthew and Abraham Mesier, Executors of the estate of Peter Mesier the elder, 1821 June 29 (Folder 22, Box 18)
    - Matthew Mesier and Margaret Mesier, widow of Peter Mesier, 1821 July 6 (Folder 23, Box 18)
    - John Suydam of the City of New York and Matthew Mesier and wife Joanna of Fishkill in Dutchess County [4 items], 1821 June 16-29 (Folder 24, Box 18)
    - David Lydig and wife Martha of the City of New York, Peter Mesier and wife Catharine of the City of New York, John Suydam and wife Jane of the City of New York and Matthew Mesier of Dutchess County, 1827 August 27 (Folder 25, Box 18)
    - Matthew Mesier and wife Joanna and Benjamin Clapp, 1827 September 3 (Folder 26, Box 18)
    - Matthew Mesier of Fishkill in Dutchess County and the Episcopal Church of Fishkill, 1831 March 8 (Folder 27, Box 18)
    - Peter Mesier and wife Mary, Matthew Mesier and wife Joanna and Walter Channing, 1811 May 4 (Folder 28, Box 18)
    - Henry Suydam of the City of New York, Executor of the estate of John Suydam, and Matthew Mesier, 1821 June 29 (Folder 29, Box 18)
    - H. Munn and Matthew Mesier, 1844 April 2 (Folder 30, Box 18)
    - Eleazar Sweet and wife Jane of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Peter McKinlay and wife Mary of the same place, 1845 June 16 (Folder 31, Box 18)
    - Joanna Mesier of Fishkill in Dutchess County and James Ingham of the same place, 1845 April 22 (Folder 32, Box 18)
    - Joanna Mesier of Fishkill in Dutchess County and James Ingham of the same place, 1845 July 1 (Folder 33, Box 18)
    - Joanna Mesier of Fishkill in Dutchess County and James Ingham of the same place, 1847 September 20 (Folder 34, Box 18)
    - Daniel McKinlay, Mary McKinlay and Edwin R. Bower and Abraham S. Mesier, Henry Mesier, Joanna E. Mesier and Maria S. Mesier, 1862 March 20 (Folder 35, Box 18)
    - William Garner of the City of New York and Abraham S. Mesier, Henry Mesier, Joanna E. Mesier and Maria S. Mesier, 1876 February 28 (Folder 36, Box 18)
    - James Halstead of Fishkill in Dutchess County and Matthew Mesier, undated (Folder 37, Box 18)
    - Matthew Mesier and wife Joanna and Benjamin Clapp, undated (Folder 38, Box 18)
    - Matthew Mesier of Fishkill in Dutchess County and George Thompson and Jeremiah […], 1825 August 3 (Folder 39, Box 18)
    - John B. Van Wyck of Poughkeepsie and Peter D. and Sarah Schenck of the City of New York, 1825 December 19 (Folder 40, Box 18)
    - John B. Van Wyck and Peter D. and Sarah Schenck of the City of New York, 1830 January (Folder 41, Box 18)
    - Matthew Mesier and William Hughson, 1836 May 1 (Folder 42, Box 18)
    - Peter Mesier of the City of New York, Matthew Mesier of Dutchess County and Walter Channing of Newport, Rhode Island, 1811 May 24 (Folder 43, Box 18)
    - Indenture, 1698 September 15 (Folder 1, Box 19)
    - Indenture, 1698 September 15 (Folder 2, Box 19)
    - Floury Stanton and Peter Mesier, 1752 February 27 (Folder 3, Box 19)
    - Floury Stanton and Peter Mesier, 1752 February 27 (Folder 4, Box 19)
    - Johannes van Vorhees of Rumbout precinct and Zacharias van Vorhees, his son, 1754 November 2 (Folder 5, Box 19)
    - Joseph Haviland and wife Margaret Henderson Haviland of the City of New York, Peter Corne and wife Elizabeth Henderson Corne of the same place, Mary Henderson of the same place and Catherine Henderson, 1755 November 18 (Folder 6, Box 19)
    - Nicholas Brewer, Nicholas Brewer, Jr. and Matthew Van Bunschoten, 1777 April 4 (Folder 7, Box 19)
    - Isaac Stoutenburgh, Philip Van Cortlandt and Peter Mesier, 1784 December 15 (Folder 8, Box 19)
    - G. Banyan of Red Hook and Henry Livingston, 1787 September 11 (Folder 9, Box 19)
    - Henry Livingston and Abraham G. Lansing, 1787 September 12 (Folder 10, Box 19)
    - Peter Mesier and John Reade, 1789 May 18 (Folder 11, Box 19)
    - Map (portion of Dutchess County showing Wappingers Falls, circa 1891 (Folder 12, Box 19)
  - Peter Mesier, 1790 - 1819; 2.2; Box: 20 Folders: 1 - 8
    - Correspondence, 1798 May 6, 1808 September 16 (Folder 1, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1790 April 16 - 1805 January 14 (Folder 2, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1799 February 19 - 1804 March 18 (Folder 3, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1818 January 25 - 1819 October 17 (Folder 4, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1808 February 12 (Folder 5, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1819 August 19 (Folder 6, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1819 September - November 20 (Folder 7, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1819 February 5 (Folder 8, Box 20)
  - Matthew Mesier, 1799 - 1835; 2.3; Box: 20 Folders: 9 - 30
    - Correspondence, 1799 May 17 - July 13 (Folder 9, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1800 October 10 (Folder 10, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1801 June 3 (Folder 11, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1801 April 11 - 1806 December 19 (Folder 12, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1800 March - 1808 March 16 (Folder 13, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1814 May 20 (Folder 14, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1815 August 30 (Folder 15, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1817 November 23 (Folder 16, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1819 September 11 (Folder 17, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1820 March 1 (Folder 18, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1821 January 26 - December 19 (Folder 19, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1829 January 1 (Folder 20, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1829 March 20 - 1838 June 6 (Folder 21, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1831 February 16 (Folder 22, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1831 November (Folder 23, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1831 February 17 (Folder 24, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1832 March 9 (Folder 25, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1833 May 20 (Folder 26, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1833 June 28 (Folder 27, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1816 July 31 (Folder 28, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1835 January (Folder 29, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1831 September 21 - November 1 (Folder 30, Box 20)
  - Other family members, 1781 - 1884; 2.4; Box: 20 Folders: 31 - 44
    - Correspondence (Joanna Mesier, wife of Matthew Mesier), 1802 June 22 - 1831 May 7 (Folder 31, Box 20)
    - Correspondence (Joanna Mesier, wife of Matthew Mesier), 1817 (Folder 32, Box 20)
    - Correspondence (Abraham and Peter Mesier), 1819 September 29 - October 24 (Folder 33, Box 20)
    - Correspondence (Mrs. George Bickham Reese), 1830 June 26 (Folder 34, Box 20)
    - Correspondence (George Bickham Reese), 1846 July 22 (Folder 35, Box 20)
    - Correspondence (George Bickham Reese?), 1853 March 26 (Folder 36, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1856 March 1 - September 29 (Folder 37, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1856 April 29 (Folder 38, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1858 November 30, 1860 June 5 (Folder 39, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1834 March 8 (Folder 40, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, undated (Folder 41, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1787 July 1 (Folder 42, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1784 - 1796 (Folder 43, Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1794 June 26 - 1831 February (Folder 44, Box 20)
  - Miscellany, 1761 - 1882; 2.5; Boxes: 21 - 23 Folders: 1 - 28, 1 - 12, 1 - 2
    - Business receipts (folder 1 of 2), 1790 April 16 - 1882 August (Folder 1, Box 21)
    - Business receipts (folder 2 of 2), 1790 April 16 - 1882 August (Folder 2, Box 21)
    - Business receipts, 1761 January 1 - 1838 (Folder 3, Box 21)
    - Will of John Wanshear [Wanshaer] of Essex County, New Jersey, 1767 March 5 (Folder 4, Box 21)
    - Will of Christina Wanshaer of Essex County, New Jersey, 1769 December 30 (Folder 5, Box 21)
    - Receipts for shares of stocks (Peter Mesier), 1792 October 1, 1803 November 5 (Folder 6, Box 21)
    - New York Society Library certificate (Peter Mesier), 1793 March 1 (Folder 7, Box 21)
    - New York Society Library certificate (Peter Mesier), 1814 June 20 (Folder 8, Box 21)
    - Petitions, 1799 March - 1819 (Folder 9, Box 21)
    - Will of Peter Mesier, 1806 January 27 (Folder 10, Box 21)
    - License granted Peter Mesier for use of a flour press, 1816 September 16 (Folder 11, Box 21)
    - Map of Matthew Mesier’s farm, 1821 March 29 (Folder 12, Box 21)
    - Memorandum regarding Highland Turnpike, 1808 (Folder 13, Box 21)
    - Estate documents (Peter Schenck), 1819 - 1837 (Folder 14, Box 21)
    - Poems, undated (Folder 15, Box 21)
    - Sketches, undated (Folder 16, Box 21)
    - Zion Episcopal Church (resolutions), 1882 October 7 (Folder 17, Box 21)
    - Will of Joanna E. Mesier, 1883 December 21 (Folder 18, Box 21)
    - Documents related to Ontario lands owned by Samuel Jones and Matthew Mesier, 1811 - 1833 (Folder 19, Box 21)
    - Agricultural Society, undated (Folder 20, Box 21)
    - Map (property of Peter Mesier in Rumbout precinct), 1776 January 17 (Folder 21, Box 21)
    - Map (lands leased by Abraham Mesier to Ira Millard), 1818 May 6 (Folder 22, Box 21)
    - Map (Zion Episcopal Church in Wappingers Falls, New York), undated (Folder 23, Box 21)
    - Payments from the estate of Peter Mesier, 1827 September 8 (Folder 24, Box 21)
    - Survey of part of Matthew Mesier’s lands, undated (Folder 25, Box 21)
    - A short history of the Mesier family, undated (Folder 26, Box 21)
    - “The Old Homestead” by Maria L. Mesier [history of the Mesier family], undated (Folder 27, Box 21)
    - School notebook of Eliza J. Mesier, undated (Folder 28, Box 21)
    - Estate of Joanna Mesier, 1882 December (Folder 1, Box 22)
    - Indenture (Jacob Loockerman and Jacob Teller), 1692 November 5 (Folder 2, Box 22)
    - Indenture (James DeLancey and John Van Aelstyn), 1749 February 25 (Folder 3, Box 22)
    - Indenture (Frances Brett and Zacharias Van Voorhis), 1768 May 10 (Folder 4, Box 22)
    - Indenture (Cornelius Bogardus and Zacharias Van Voorhis), 1772 April 28 (Folder 5, Box 22)
    - Indenture (David Lydig and wife Maria), 1827 September 7 (Folder 6, Box 22)
    - Indenture (Nicholas B. Brower and John E. Seaman), undated (Folder 7, Box 22)
    - Lease (Joanna Mesier lease offered to James Ingham), undated (Folder 8, Box 22)
    - Abstracts and titles of the Mesier Estates of Wappingers Falls, circa 1800s (Folder 9, Box 22)
    - Abstracts and titles of the Mesier Estates of Wappingers Falls, circa 1800s (Folder 10, Box 22)
    - Abstracts and titles of the Mesier Estates of Wappingers Falls, circa 1800s (Folder 11, Box 22)
    - Abstracts and titles of the Mesier Estates of Wappingers Falls, circa 1800s (Folder 12, Box 22)